And welcome to Introduction to Generative AI.
欢迎来到生成式AI入门课程。
And I am the artificial intelligence
我是谷歌云的人工智能
technical curriculum developer here at Google Cloud.
技术课程开发者。
In this course, you learn to define generative AI,
在这门课程中，您将学会定义生成式AI，
explain how generative AI works, describe generative AI model
解释生成式AI的工作原理，描述生成式AI模型
Generative AI is a type of artificial intelligence
生成式AI是一种人工智能
technology that can produce various types of content,
技术，可以生成各种类型的内容，
including text, imagery, audio, and synthetic data.
包括文本、图像、音频和合成数据。
let's provide a bit of context.
那么让我们提供一些背景信息。
So two very common questions asked
所以两个非常常见的问题是
are what is artificial intelligence
什么是人工智能
and what is the difference between AI and machine
以及人工智能和机器
learning.
学习之间的区别是什么。
One way to think about it is that AI is a discipline,
可以这样认为，AI是一门学科，
like physics for example.
例如物理学。
AI is a branch of computer science
AI是计算机科学的一个分支
that deals with the creation of intelligence agents, which
它涉及到智能代理的创建，这些代理
Essentially, AI has to do with the theory and methods
从本质上讲，AI与理论和方法有关
to build machines that think and act like humans.
构建像人类一样思考和行动的机器。
In this discipline, we have machine learning,
在这个学科中，我们有机器学习，
It is a program or system that trains a model from input data.
这是一个从输入数据中训练模型的程序或系统。
That trained model can make useful predictions
经过训练的模型可以对
from new or never before seen data
从未见过的新数据进行有用的预测，
drawn from the same one used to train the model.
这些数据来自于用于训练模型的相同数据。
Machine learning gives the computer
机器学习赋予计算机
the ability to learn without explicit programming.
在没有明确编程的情况下学习的能力。
Two of the most common classes of machine learning models
两种最常见的机器学习模型类别
are unsupervised and supervised ML models.
是无监督和有监督的ML模型。
The key difference between the two
两者之间的关键区别
is that, with supervised models, we have labels.
是有监督模型具有标签。
Labeled data is data that comes with a tag like a name, a type,
带标签的数据是带有标签的数据，如名称、类型、
or a number.
或数字。
Unlabeled data is data that comes with no tag.
无标签数据是没有标签的数据。
This graph is an example of the problem
这张图是一个例子，
that a supervised model might try to solve.
说明了有监督模型可能尝试解决的问题。
For example, let's say you are the owner of a restaurant.
例如，假设您是一家餐厅的老板。
You have historical data of the bill amount
您拥有账单金额的历史数据
and how much different people tipped based on order type
以及基于订单类型不同人给予的小费
and whether it was picked up or delivered.
以及是自取还是送货上门。
In supervised learning, the model learns from past examples
在监督学习中，模型通过过去的例子学习
to predict future values, in this case tips.
来预测未来的值，本例中是小费。
So here the model uses the total bill amount
所以在这里，模型使用总账单金额
to predict the future tip amount based on whether an order was
根据订单是自取还是送货上门来预测未来的小费金额。
that an unsupervised model might try to solve.
无监督模型可能尝试解决的问题。
So here you want to look at tenure and income
所以在这里你想看的是工龄和收入
Unsupervised problems are all about discovery,
无监督问题都是关于发现的，
about looking at the raw data and seeing if it naturally
关于观察原始数据，看它是否自然地
falls into groups.
分成几组。
Let's get a little deeper and show this graphically
让我们更深入地用图形展示这些概念，
as understanding these concepts are
因为理解这些概念是
the foundation for your understanding of generative AI.
你理解生成式AI的基础。
In supervised learning, testing data values or x
在监督学习中，测试数据值或x
are input into the model.
被输入到模型中。
The model outputs a prediction and compares that prediction
模型输出预测并将该预测
to the training data used to train the model.
与用于训练模型的训练数据进行比较。
If the predicted test data values and actual training data
如果预测的测试数据值和实际训练数据值
values are far apart, that's called error.
相差很大，那就叫做误差。
And the model tries to reduce this error
模型试图减少这种误差，
until the predicted and actual values are closer together.
直到预测值和实际值更接近为止。
This is a classic optimization problem.
这是一个经典的优化问题。
Now that we've explored the difference
现在我们已经探讨了
between artificial intelligence and machine learning,
人工智能和机器学习之间的区别，
and supervised and unsupervised learning,
以及监督学习和无监督学习，
let's briefly explore where deep learning
让我们简要探讨深度学习
fits as a subset of machine learning methods.
在机器学习方法中的位置。
While machine learning is a broad field that
虽然机器学习是一个涵盖了
encompasses many different techniques,
许多不同技术的广泛领域，
allowing them to process more complex patterns than machine
使它们能够处理比机器学习更复杂的模式。
Artificial neural networks are inspired by the human brain.
人工神经网络受到人脑的启发。
They are made up of many interconnected nodes or neurons
它们由许多相互连接的节点或神经元组成，
that can learn to perform tasks by processing data and making
通过处理数据和进行预测来学习执行任务。
Deep learning models typically have many layers
深度学习模型通常具有许多层次
of neurons, which allows them to learn
的神经元，这使得它们能够学习
more complex patterns than traditional machine learning
比传统机器学习更复杂的模式
models.
模型。
And neural networks can use both labeled and unlabeled data.
神经网络可以使用有标签和无标签的数据。
This is called semi-supervised learning.
这被称为半监督学习。
In semi-supervised learning, a neural network
在半监督学习中，神经网络
is trained on a small amount of labeled data
在少量有标签数据上进行训练
and a large amount of unlabeled data.
和大量无标签数据。
The labeled data helps the neural network
有标签数据帮助神经网络
to learn the basic concepts of the task
学习任务的基本概念
while the unlabeled data helps the neural network
而无标签数据帮助神经网络
to generalize to new examples.
概括到新的例子。
Now we finally get to where generative AI
现在我们终于来到了生成式AI
fits into this AI discipline.
融入这个AI学科的地方。
Gen AI is a subset of deep learning, which
生成式AI是深度学习的一个子集，
means it uses artificial neural networks,
这意味着它使用人工神经网络，
can process both labeled and unlabeled data using
可以使用有监督、无监督和半监督方法
supervised, unsupervised, and semi-supervised methods.
处理标记和未标记的数据。
Large language models are also a subset of deep learning.
大型语言模型也是深度学习的一个子集。
Deep learning models, or machine learning models in general,
深度学习模型，或者一般的机器学习模型，
can be divided into two types, generative and discriminative.
可以分为两种类型，生成式和判别式。
A discriminative model is a type of model
判别模型是一种类型的模型
that is used to classify or predict labels for data points.
用于对数据点进行分类或预测标签。
Discriminative models are typically
判别模型通常
And they learn the relationship between the features
它们学习数据点的特征
of the data points and the labels.
和标签之间的关系。
Once a discriminative model is trained,
一旦判别模型被训练好，
it can be used to predict the label for new data points.
它可以用来预测新数据点的标签。
A generative model generates new data instances
生成模型根据现有数据的概率分布生成新的数据实例
based on a learned probability distribution of existing data.
基于学习到的概率分布。
Thus generative models generate new content.
因此生成模型会生成新内容。
The discriminative model learns the conditional probability
判别模型学习条件概率
distribution or the probability of y,
分布或者y的概率，
our output, given x, our input, that this is a dog
我们的输出，给定x，我们的输入，这是一只狗
The generative model learns the joint probability distribution
生成模型学习联合概率分布
or the probability of x and y and predicts
或者x和y的概率，并预测
the conditional probability that this is a dog
这是一只狗的条件概率
and can then generate a picture of a dog.
然后可以生成一张狗的图片。
So to summarize, generative models
所以总结一下，生成模型
can generate new data instances while discriminative models
可以生成新的数据实例，而判别模型
discriminate between different kinds of data instances.
在不同类型的数据实例之间进行区分。
The top image shows a traditional machine
顶部图片展示了一个传统的机器
learning model which attempts to learn
学习模型，试图学习
the relationship between the data and the label,
数据与标签之间的关系，
or what you want to predict.
或者你想要预测的内容。
The bottom image shows a generative AI model
底部图片展示了一个生成性AI模型
which attempts to learn patterns on content so that it
试图学习内容上的模式，以便它
can generate new content.
可以生成新的内容。
A good way to distinguish what is gen AI and what is not
区分什么是通用人工智能和什么不是的一个好方法
is shown in this illustration.
就是通过这幅插图来展示。
It is not gen AI when the output, or y, or label is
当输出、或者y、或者标签是
a number or a class, for example spam or not spam,
一个数字或一个类别，例如垃圾邮件或非垃圾邮件，
or a probability.
或者一个概率时，它不是通用人工智能。
It is gen AI when the output is natural language, like speech
当输出是自然语言，如语音
or text, an image or audio, for example.
或文本、图像或音频等时，它是通用人工智能。
Visualizing this mathematically would look like this.
从数学角度来看，这样的可视化效果如下。
the y is equal to f of x equation calculates
y 等于 f(x) 方程计算
the dependent output of a process given different inputs.
给定不同输入的过程的依赖输出。
The y stands for the model output.
y 代表模型输出。
The f embodies the function used in the calculation.
f 代表用于计算的函数。
So the model output is a function of all the inputs.
所以模型输出是所有输入的函数。
If the y is the number, like predicted sales,
如果 y 是一个数字，比如预测的销售额，
it is not gen AI.
那么它不是生成 AI。
If y is a sentence, like define sales,
如果 y 是一个句子，比如定义销售额，
it is generative as the question would elicit a text response.
那么它是生成性的，因为问题会引发一个文本回应。
The response would be based on all the massive large data
回应将基于所有大量的大数据
the model was already trained on.
模型已经接受过训练。
To summarize at a high level, the traditional, classical
总结一下高层次的传统、经典的
supervised and unsupervised learning process
监督和无监督学习过程
Depending on the use case or problem,
根据用例或问题，
the model can give you a prediction.
模型可以给出预测。
It can classify something or cluster something.
它可以对某物进行分类或聚类。
We use this example to show you how much more robust
我们用这个例子来展示
the gen AI process is.
gen AI过程有多强大。
The gen AI process can take training code, label data,
gen AI过程可以采用训练代码、标签数据，
and build a foundation model.
来构建基础模型。
The foundation model can then generate new content.
基础模型可以生成新的内容。
For example, text, code, images, audio, video, et cetera.
例如，文本、代码、图像、音频、视频等。
We've come a long away from traditional programming
我们已经从传统编程
to neural networks to generative models.
走到了神经网络和生成模型。
In traditional programming, we used
在传统编程中，我们需要
to have to hard code the rules for distinguishing a cat--
硬编码区分猫的规则——
the type, animal; legs, four; ears, two; fur, yes;
类型，动物；腿，四；耳朵，两个；毛发，有；
likes yarn and catnip.
喜欢纱线和猫薄荷。
could give the network pictures of cats and dogs
可以给网络提供猫和狗的图片
and ask is this a cat and it would predict a cat.
然后询问这是不是猫，它会预测出是猫。
In the generative wave, we as users
在生成波中，我们作为用户
can generate our own content, whether it
可以生成我们自己的内容，无论是
be text, images, audio, video, et cetera, for example
文本、图像、音频、视频等等，例如
or LAMBDA, Language Model for Dialogue Applications,
或者LAMBDA，用于对话应用的语言模型，
ingest very, very large data from the multiple sources
从互联网的多个来源中摄取非常非常大的数据
models we can use simply by asking a question,
建立我们可以简单地通过提问来使用的基础语言
whether typing it into a prompt or verbally
模型，无论是将问题输入到提示中还是口头
talking into the prompt itself.
与提示本身进行对话。
So when you ask it what's a cat, it
所以当你问它什么是猫时，它
can give you everything it has learned about a cat.
可以告诉你它所了解的关于猫的一切。
Now we come to our formal definition.
现在我们来到我们的正式定义。
Gen AI is a type of artificial intelligence
生成式AI是一种人工智能类型
learned from existing content.
创造新内容。
The process of learning from existing content
从现有内容中学习的过程
is called training and results in the creation
被称为训练，并产生一个统计模型
of a statistical model when given a prompt.
在给定提示(Prompt)时。
AI uses the model to predict what an expected response might
AI使用模型来预测预期响应可能是什么
be and this generates new content.
从而生成新的内容。
Essentially, it learns the underlying structure
本质上，它学习了数据的基本结构
of the data and can then generate
然后可以生成
new samples that are similar to the data it was trained on.
与其训练数据相似的新样本。
As previously mentioned, a generative language model
如前所述，生成性语言模型
can take what it has learned from the examples it's
可以从它所看到的示例中学到东西
been shown and create something entirely new
然后根据这些信息创造出全新的东西
based on that information.
基于这些信息。
Large language models are one type of generative AI
大型语言模型是一种生成性AI
since they generate novel combinations of text
因为它们生成了新颖的文本组合
in the form of natural sounding language.
以自然 sounding 语言的形式。
A generative image model takes an image
生成图像模型接受图像作为输入
as input and can output text, another image, or video.
可以输出文本、另一个图像或视频。
For example, under the output text,
例如，在输出文本下，
you can get visual question answering
您可以获得视觉问题回答
while under output image, an image completion is generated.
而在输出图像下，生成图像补全。
And under output video, animation is generated.
在输出视频下，生成动画。
A generative language model takes text as input
生成语言模型以文本为输入
and can output more text, an image, audio, or decisions.
可以输出更多文本、图像、音频或决策。
For example, under the output text,
例如，在输出文本下，
question answering is generated.
生成问题回答。
And under output image, a video is generated.
在输出图像下，生成了一个视频。
We've stated that generative language models learn
我们已经声明过，生成性语言模型通过训练数据学习
about patterns and language through training data,
关于模式和语言的知识，
then, given some text, they predict what comes next.
然后，给定一些文本，它们预测接下来会发生什么。
Thus generative language models are pattern matching systems.
因此生成性语言模型是模式匹配系统。
They learn about patterns based on the data you provide.
它们根据您提供的数据学习关于模式的知识。
Here is an example.
这里有一个例子。
Based on things it's learned from its training data,
基于它从训练数据中学到的东西，
it offers predictions of how to complete this sentence,
它提供了如何完成这个句子的预测，
I'm making a sandwich with peanut butter and jelly.
我正在用花生酱和果冻做三明治。
Here is the same example using Bard,
这里有一个使用Bard的相同示例，
which is trained on a massive amount of text data
它接受大量的文本数据训练，
and is able to communicate and generate
能够与人类沟通并生成
humanlike text in response to a wide range of prompts
针对各种提示和问题的类人文本。
Here is another example.
这是另一个例子。
The meaning of life is--
生命的意义是--
The power of generative AI comes from the use of transformers.
生成式AI的力量来自于使用 Transformers 。
Transformers produced a 2018 revolution
Transformers 在2018年引发了自然语言处理的革命
At a high level, a transformer model
在较高层次上，Transformers 模型
consists of an encoder and decoder.
由编码器和解码器组成。
The encoder encodes the input sequence
编码器对输入序列进行编码
learns how to decode the representation
学会如何解码表示
for a relevant task.
以完成相关任务。
In transformers, hallucinations are words or phrases
在 Transformers 中，幻觉（Hallucinations）是
that are generated by the model that
由模型生成的单词或短语
are often nonsensical or grammatically incorrect.
它们通常是无意义的或语法不正确的。
Hallucinations can be caused by a number of factors,
幻觉可能由多种因素引起，
including the model is not trained on enough data,
包括模型没有接受足够的数据训练，
or the model is trained on noisy or dirty data,
或者模型接受了噪声或脏数据的训练，
or the model is not given enough context,
或者模型没有获得足够的上下文，
or the model is not given enough constraints.
或者模型没有获得足够的约束。
because they can make the output text difficult to understand.
因为它们可能使输出文本难以理解。
likely to generate incorrect or misleading information.
容易产生错误或误导性的信息。
A prompt is a short piece of text
提示（Prompt）是一小段文本，
that is given to the large language model as input.
作为输入提供给大型语言模型。
And it can be used to control the output of the model
并且它可以用于以多种方式控制模型的输出
Prompt design is the process of creating
提示设计是创建的过程
a prompt that will generate the desired output
一个将产生所需输出的提示
from a large language model.
从一个大型语言模型。
As previously mentioned, gen AI depends a lot
如前所述，gen AI很大程度上取决于
on the training data that you have fed into it.
您输入的训练数据。
And it analyzes the patterns and structures of the input data
它分析输入数据的模式和结构
and thus learns.
从而学习。
But with access to a browser based prompt, you, the user,
但是通过访问基于浏览器的提示，您，用户，
can generate your own content.
可以生成您自己的内容。
We've shown illustrations of the types of input based upon data.
我们展示了基于数据的输入类型的示例。
Here are the associated model types.
这里是相关的模型类型。
Text-to-text.
文本到文本。
Text-to-text models take a natural language input
文本到文本模型接受自然语言输入
and produces a text output.
并生成文本输出。
These models are trained to learn the mapping
这些模型被训练来学习映射
between a pair of text, e.g.
在一对文本之间，例如。
for example, translation from one language to another.
例如，从一种语言翻译成另一种语言。
Text-to-image.
文本到图像。
Text-to-image models are trained on a large set of images,
文本到图像模型在大量图像集上进行训练，
each captioned with a short text description.
每个图像都配有简短的文本描述。
Diffusion is one method used to achieve this.
扩散（Diffusion）是实现这一目标的一种方法。
Text-to-video and text-to-3D.
文本到视频和文本到3D。
Text-to-video models aim to generate a video representation
文本到视频模型旨在从文本输入生成视频表示
from text input.
从文本输入。
The input text can be anything from a single sentence
输入文本可以是从单个句子
to a full script.
到完整的剧本。
And the output is a video that corresponds to the input text.
输出是与输入文本相对应的视频。
Similarly, text-to-3D models generate
类似地，文本到3D模型生成
three dimensional objects that correspond to a user's text
与用户文本相对应的三维对象描述。
For example, this can be used in games or other 3D worlds.
例如，这可以用于游戏或其他3D世界。
Text-to-task.
文本到任务。
Text-to-task models are trained to perform a defined task
文本到任务模型经过训练以执行明确定义的任务
or action based on text input.
或基于文本输入的操作。
This task can be a wide range of actions
这个任务可以是广泛的操作范围
such as answering a question, performing a search,
例如回答问题、执行搜索、
making a prediction, or taking some sort of action.
进行预测或采取某种行动。
For example, a text-to-task model
例如，一个文本到任务模型
could be trained to navigate a web UI or make changes to a doc
可以被训练来导航Web UI或通过GUI对文档进行更改。
on a vast quantity of data designed to be adapted or fine
在大量数据上设计以适应或精细
tuned to a wide range of downstream tasks,
调整到各种下游任务，
such as sentiment analysis, image captioning, and object
如情感分析、图像标注和对象识别。
Foundation models have the potential
基础模型具有潜力
to revolutionize many industries, including
彻底改变许多行业，包括
health care, finance, and customer service.
医疗保健、金融和客户服务。
They can be used to detect fraud and provide
它们可以用来检测欺诈并提供
personalized customer support.
个性化客户支持。
Vertex AI offers a model garden that
Vertex AI 提供了一个模型花园，
includes foundation models.
其中包括基础模型。
The language foundation models include
语言基础模型包括
PaLM API for chat and text.
PaLM API 用于聊天和文本。
The vision foundation models includes stable diffusion,
视觉基础模型包括稳定扩散，
which has been shown to be effective at generating
已被证明在根据文本描述生成
high quality images from text descriptions.
高质量图像方面非常有效。
Let's say you have a use case where
假设您有一个用例，
you need to gather sentiments about how your customers are
您需要收集关于客户对您的产品或服务的感受。
You can use the classification task sentiment analysis task
您可以使用分类任务情感分析任务
model for just that purpose.
就是为这个目的设计的模型。
And what if you needed to perform occupancy analytics?
那么，如果您需要进行占用分析呢？
There is a task model for your use case.
有一个任务模型适用于您的用例。
Shown here are gen AI applications.
这里展示的是通用人工智能应用。
Let's look at an example of code generation
让我们看一个代码生成的例子
shown in the second block under code at the top.
在顶部代码下的第二个块中显示。
In this example, I've input a code file conversion problem,
在这个例子中，我输入了一个代码文件转换问题，
converting from Python to JSON.
从Python转换为JSON。
I use Bard.
我使用Bard。
And I insert into the prompt box the following.
我在提示框中插入以下内容。
I have a Pandas DataFrame with two columns, one with the file
我有一个Pandas DataFrame，有两列，一列是文件名，
name and one with the hour in which it is generated.
另一列是生成它的小时。
I'm trying to convert this into a JSON file
我试图将其转换为JSON文件
in the format shown onscreen.
以屏幕上显示的格式。
Bard returns the steps I need to do this and the code snippet.
Bard返回我需要执行此操作的步骤和代码片段。
And here my output is in a JSON format.
这里我的输出是JSON格式。
It gets better.
它变得更好了。
I happen to be using Google's free, browser-based Jupyter
我碰巧在使用谷歌的免费、基于浏览器的Jupyter
Notebook, known as Colab.
Notebook，也被称为Colab。
And I simply export the Python code to Google's Colab.
我只需将Python代码导出到谷歌的Colab。
To summarize, Bart code generation
简而言之，Bart代码生成
can help you debug your lines of source code,
可以帮助您调试源代码的行，
explain your code to you line by line,
逐行向您解释代码，
craft SQL queries for your database,
为您的数据库编写SQL查询，
translate code from one language to another,
将代码从一种语言翻译成另一种语言，
and generate documentation and tutorials for source code.
并为源代码生成文档和教程。
Generative AI Studio lets you quickly explore and customize
生成AI工作室让您快速浏览和自定义
gen AI models that you can leverage in your applications
您可以在谷歌云中应用的生成AI模型。
Gen AI models by providing a variety of tools and resources
Gen AI模型，提供各种工具和资源
that make it easy to get started.
让您轻松入门。
For example, there's a library of pre-trained models.
例如，有一个预先训练模型的库。
There is a tool for fine tuning models.
有一个用于微调模型的工具。
There is a tool for deploying models to production.
有一个将模型部署到生产环境的工具。
And there is a community forum for developers
还有一个供开发者社区论坛
to share ideas and collaborate.
可以分享想法和协作。
Generative AI App Builder lets you
生成性AI应用程序构建器让您
create gen AI apps without having to write any code.
无需编写任何代码即可创建生成性AI应用。
Gen AI App Builder has a drag and drop interface
Gen AI应用程序构建器具有拖放界面
that makes it easy to design and build apps.
使设计和构建应用程序变得简单。
It has a visual editor that makes
它有一个可视化编辑器，使得
it easy to create and edit app content.
轻松创建和编辑应用程序内容。
It has a built-in search engine that
它内置了一个搜索引擎，
allows users to search for information within the app.
允许用户在应用程序内搜索信息。
And it has a conversational AI Engine
并且它有一个会话式AI引擎
that helps users to interact with the app using
帮助用户使用
natural language.
自然语言与应用程序互动。
You can create your own digital assistants, custom search
您可以创建自己的数字助手、自定义搜索
engines, knowledge bases, training applications,
引擎、知识库、培训应用程序，
and much more.
以及更多。
PaLM API lets you test and experiment
PaLM API允许您测试和实验
with Google's large language models and gen AI tools.
使用谷歌的大型语言模型和通用AI工具。
To make prototyping quick and more accessible,
为了使原型设计更快速、更易于访问，
developers can integrate PaLM API with Maker suite
开发者可以将PaLM API与Maker套件集成
and use it to access the API using a graphical user
并使用它通过图形用户界面访问API。
The suite includes a number of different tools such as a model
该套件包括许多不同的工具，如模型
training tool, a model deployment tool, and a model
训练工具、模型部署工具和模型
monitoring tool.
监控工具。
The model training tool helps developers train ML models
模型训练工具帮助开发者使用不同的算法
on their data using different algorithms.
在他们的数据上训练机器学习模型。
The model deployment tool helps developers deploy ML models
模型部署工具帮助开发者部署机器学习模型
to production with a number of different deployment options.
提供多种不同的部署选项。
The model monitoring tool helps developers
模型监控工具帮助开发者
monitor the performance of their ML models
监控他们的机器学习模型在生产中的性能
in production using a dashboard and a number
使用仪表板和多种不同的指标。
Thank you for watching our course, Introduction
感谢您收看我们的课程，介绍
to Generative AI.
生成式人工智能。